[{"text": "ENGLISH[ENT0:NORP]\nAPPLE INC.[ENT1:ORG]\nSOFTWARE LICENSE AGREEMENT FOR macOS Sequoia[ENT2:PERSON]\nFor use on Apple[ENT3:ORG]-branded Systems\nPLEASE READ THIS SOFTWARE LICENSE AGREEMENT (“LICENSE”) CAREFULLY BEFORE \nUSING THE APPLE SOFTWARE.  BY USING THE APPLE SOFTWARE, YOU ARE AGREEING TO BE \nBOUND BY THE TERMS OF THIS LICENSE.  IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS \nLICENSE, DO NOT INSTALL AND/OR USE THE APPLE SOFTWARE AND, IF PRESENTED WITH \nTHE OPTION TO “AGREE” OR “DISAGREE[ENT4:WORK_OF_ART]” TO THE TERMS, CLICK “DISAGREE[ENT5:WORK_OF_ART]”. IF YOU \nACQUIRED THE APPLE SOFTWARE AS PART OF AN APPLE HARDWARE PURCHASE AND IF YOU \nDO NOT AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS LICENSE, YOU MAY RETURN THE ENTIRE APPLE \nHARDWARE/SOFTWARE PACKAGE WITHIN THE RETURN PERIOD TO THE APPLE STORE OR \nAUTHORIZED DISTRIBUTOR WHERE YOU OBTAINED IT FOR A REFUND, SUBJECT TO APPLE[ENT6:ORG]’S \nRETURN POLICY FOUND AT https://www.apple.com/legal/sales-support/. YOU MUST RETURN \nTHE ENTIRE HARDWARE/SOFTWARE PACKAGE IN[ENT7:ORG] ORDER TO OBTAIN A REFUND.\nIMPORTANT NOTE: To the extent that this software may be used to reproduce, modify, publish or \ndistribute materials, it is licensed to you only for reproduction, modiﬁcation, publication and \ndistribution of non-copyrighted materials, materials in which you own the copyright, or materials \nyou are authorized or legally permitted to reproduce, modify, publish or distribute. If you are \nuncertain about your right to copy, modify, publish or distribute any material, you should contact \nyour legal advisor.\n1[ENT8:CARDINAL]. General.\nA. The Apple[ENT9:ORG] software (including Boot ROM[ENT10:PERSON] code), any third[ENT11:ORDINAL] party software, documentation, interfaces, \ncontent, fonts and any data accompanying this License (“Original Apple Software”), as may be updated \nor replaced by feature enhancements, software updates, security responses, system ﬁles, or system \nrestore software provided by Apple[ENT12:ORG] for your Apple[ENT13:ORG]-branded computer or supported peripheral device \n(“Apple Software Changes”), whether preinstalled on Apple[ENT14:ORG]-branded hardware, on internal storage, on", "entities": [["ENGLISH", "NORP"], ["APPLE INC.", "ORG"], ["macOS Sequoia", "PERSON"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["DISAGREE", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["DISAGREE", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["APPLE", "ORG"], ["THE ENTIRE HARDWARE/SOFTWARE PACKAGE IN", "ORG"], ["1", "CARDINAL"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Boot ROM", "PERSON"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"]], "relations": [["APPLE INC.", "produced_by", "Apple"], ["APPLE INC.", "produced_by", "APPLE"], ["APPLE INC.", "produced_by", "Apple"], ["APPLE INC.", "produced_by", "Apple"], ["APPLE INC.", "produced_by", "Apple"], ["macOS Sequoia", "contains", "DISAGREE"], ["macOS Sequoia", "contains", "DISAGREE"], ["Boot ROM", "related_to", "APPLE INC."]]}, {"text": "restore software provided by Apple[ENT0:ORG] for your Apple[ENT1:ORG]-branded computer or supported peripheral device \n(“Apple Software Changes”), whether preinstalled on Apple[ENT2:ORG]-branded hardware, on internal storage, on \nremovable media, on disk, in read only memory, on any other media or in any other form (the Original \nApple Software[ENT3:ORG] and Apple Software Changes[ENT4:ORG] are collectively referred to as the “Apple Software[ENT5:ORG]”), are \nlicensed, not sold, to you by Apple Inc.[ENT6:ORG] (“Apple[ENT7:ORG]”) for use only under the terms of this License[ENT8:ORG]. Apple[ENT9:ORG] and/\nor Apple[ENT10:ORG]’s licensors retain ownership of the Apple Software[ENT11:ORG] itself and reserve all rights not expressly \ngranted to you. You agree that the terms of this License[ENT12:ORG] will apply to any Apple[ENT13:ORG]-branded application \nsoftware product that may be preinstalled on your Apple[ENT14:ORG]-branded hardware, unless such product is \naccompanied by a separate license, in which case you agree that the terms of that license will govern \nyour use of that product.\nB. Apple[ENT15:ORG], at its discretion, may make available future Apple Software Changes[ENT16:ORG]. Apple Software \nChanges[ENT17:ORG], if any, may not necessarily include all existing software features or new features that Apple[ENT18:ORG] \nreleases for newer or other models of Apple[ENT19:ORG]-branded computers. The terms of this License[ENT20:ORG] will govern \nany Apple Software Changes[ENT21:ORG] provided by Apple[ENT22:ORG], unless such Apple Software Changes[ENT23:ORG] are accompanied \nby a separate license, in which case the terms of that license will govern.\nC. Title[ENT24:ORG] and intellectual property rights in and to any content displayed by or accessed through the Apple[ENT25:ORG] \nSoftware belongs to the respective content owner. Such content may be protected by copyright or other \nintellectual property laws and treaties, and may be subject to terms of use of the third[ENT26:ORDINAL] party providing \nsuch content. Except as otherwise provided herein, this License[ENT27:ORG] does not grant you any rights to use", "entities": [["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Original \nApple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple Software Changes", "ORG"], ["the “Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple Inc.", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["B. Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Software Changes", "ORG"], ["Apple Software \nChanges", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"], ["Apple Software Changes", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Software Changes", "ORG"], ["C. Title", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["License", "ORG"]], "relations": [["Apple", "provides", "Apple"], ["Apple", "is branded for", "Apple"], ["Apple", "includes", "the Original \nApple Software"], ["the Original \nApple Software", "is part of", "Apple Software Changes"], ["Apple Software Changes", "is collectively referred to as", "the “Apple Software"], ["the “Apple Software", "is licensed by", "Apple Inc."], ["Apple Inc.", "is also known as", "Apple"], ["License", "governs", "License"], ["Apple", "retains ownership of", "Apple"], ["the Apple Software", "is subject to", "License"], ["B. Apple", "may provide", "Apple Software Changes"], ["Apple Software \nChanges", "may not include", "Apple"], ["License", "governs", "Apple Software Changes"], ["Apple", "is provided by", "third"], ["License", "does not grant rights to", "C. Title"]]}, {"text": "such content. Except as otherwise provided herein, this License[ENT0:ORG] does not grant you any rights to use \nsuch content nor does it guarantee that such content will continue to be available to you. You are prohibited from republishing, retransmitting or reproducing any images accessed through News or Maps \nas a stand-alone ﬁle.\n2[ENT1:CARDINAL]. Permitted License Uses and Restrictions.\nA. Preinstalled and Single-Copy Apple Software License. Subject to the terms and conditions of this \nLicense, unless you obtained the Apple Software[ENT2:ORG] from the Mac App Store[ENT3:WORK_OF_ART], through an automatic \ndownload or under a volume license, maintenance or other written agreement from Apple[ENT4:ORG], you are \ngranted a limited, non-exclusive license to install, use and run one[ENT5:CARDINAL] (1[ENT6:CARDINAL]) copy of the Apple Software[ENT7:ORG] on a \nsingle Apple[ENT8:ORG]-branded computer at any one[ENT9:CARDINAL] time. For example, these single-copy license terms apply to \nyou if you obtained the Apple Software[ENT10:ORG] preinstalled on Apple[ENT11:ORG]-branded hardware.\nB. Mac App Store License[ENT12:ORG]. If you obtained a license for the Apple Software[ENT13:ORG] from the Mac App Store[ENT14:WORK_OF_ART] or \nthrough an automatic download, then subject to the terms and conditions of this License[ENT15:ORG] and as \npermitted by the Services and Content Usage Rules[ENT16:ORG] set forth in the Apple Media Services[ENT17:ORG] Terms and \nConditions (https://www.apple.com/legal/internet-services/itunes/) (“Usage Rules”), you are granted a \nlimited, non-transferable, non-exclusive license:\n(i) to download, install, use and run for personal, non-commercial use, one[ENT18:CARDINAL] (1[ENT19:CARDINAL]) copy of the Apple \nSoftware[ENT20:ORG] directly on each Apple[ENT21:ORG]-branded computer running macOS Sonoma[ENT22:GPE], macOS Ventura[ENT23:GPE], \nmacOS Monterey[ENT24:PERSON], macOS Big Sur, macOS Catalina, macOS Mojave[ENT25:PERSON], or macOS High Sierra[ENT26:ORG]  \n(“Mac Computer[ENT27:WORK_OF_ART]”) that you own or control;\n(ii) If you are a commercial enterprise or educational institution, to download, install, use and run \none[ENT28:CARDINAL] (1[ENT29:CARDINAL]) copy of the Apple Software[ENT30:ORG] for use either: (a) by a single individual on each of the Mac[ENT31:PERSON]", "entities": [["License", "ORG"], ["2", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Mac App Store", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["one", "CARDINAL"], ["1", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["one", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["B. Mac App Store License", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Mac App Store", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["License", "ORG"], ["the Services and Content Usage Rules", "ORG"], ["the Apple Media Services", "ORG"], ["one", "CARDINAL"], ["1", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple \nSoftware", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Sonoma", "GPE"], ["Ventura", "GPE"], ["macOS Monterey", "PERSON"], ["macOS Mojave", "PERSON"], ["macOS High Sierra", "ORG"], ["Mac Computer", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["one", "CARDINAL"], ["1", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Mac", "PERSON"]], "relations": [["License", "grants_license", "License"], ["the Apple Software", "obtained_from", "Apple"], ["Mac App Store", "related_to", "Mac App Store"], ["Apple", "related_to", "Apple"], ["the Apple Software", "related_to", "the Apple \nSoftware"], ["B. Mac App Store License", "related_to", "the Services and Content Usage Rules"], ["the Apple Media Services", "related_to", "Sonoma"], ["Apple", "related_to", "Mac Computer"]]}, {"text": "one[ENT0:CARDINAL] (1[ENT1:CARDINAL]) copy of the Apple Software[ENT2:ORG] for use either: (a) by a single individual on each of the Mac \nComputer(s) that you own or control, or (b) by multiple individuals on a single shared Mac \nComputer[ENT3:ORG] that you own or control. For example, a single employee may use the Apple Software[ENT4:ORG] \non both the employee’s desktop Mac Computer[ENT5:ORG] and laptop Mac Computer[ENT6:ORG], or multiple students \nmay serially use the Apple Software[ENT7:ORG] on a single Mac Computer[ENT8:ORG] located at a resource center or \nlibrary; and \n(iii) to install, use and run up to two[ENT9:CARDINAL] (2[ENT10:CARDINAL]) additional copies or instances of the Apple Software[ENT11:ORG], or \nany prior macOS or OS X operating system software or subsequent release of the Apple \nSoftware[ENT12:ORG], within virtual operating system environments on each Apple[ENT13:ORG]-branded computer you \nown or control that is already running the Apple Software[ENT14:ORG], for purposes of: (a) software \ndevelopment; (b) testing during software development; (c) using macOS Server; or (d) personal, \nnon-commercial use.\nExcept as expressly permitted in Section 3[ENT15:LAW], the grant set forth in Section 2B(iii[ENT16:LAW]) above does not permit \nyou to use the virtualized copies or instances of the Apple Software[ENT17:ORG] in connection with service bureau, \ntime-sharing, terminal sharing, relay service or other similar types of services. Except as expressly \npermitted in this Section 2B[ENT18:LAW], you may not use the Apple Software[ENT19:ORG] to run any Apple[ENT20:ORG] operating system \nsoftware, including iOS, iPadOS, watchOS or tvOS, in virtual operating system environments on Mac \nComputer(s).\nC. Volume[ENT21:ORG] or Maintenance License[ENT22:ORG]. If you obtained the Apple Software[ENT23:ORG] under a volume or maintenance \nlicense program with Apple[ENT24:ORG], the terms of your volume or maintenance license will determine the number \nof copies of the Apple Software[ENT25:ORG] you are permitted to download, install, use and run on Apple[ENT26:ORG]-branded \ncomputers you own or control.  Except as agreed to in writing by Apple[ENT27:ORG], all other terms and conditions", "entities": [["one", "CARDINAL"], ["1", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Mac \nComputer", "ORG"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Mac Computer", "ORG"], ["Mac Computer", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Mac Computer", "ORG"], ["up to two", "CARDINAL"], ["2", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Apple \nSoftware", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Section 3", "LAW"], ["Section 2B(iii", "LAW"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Section 2B", "LAW"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["C. Volume", "ORG"], ["Maintenance License", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"]], "relations": [["the Apple Software", "uses", "Apple Software"], ["Apple Software", "is_a", "the Apple Software"], ["the Apple Software", "is_related_to", "the Apple \nSoftware"], ["the Apple \nSoftware", "is_a", "the Apple Software"], ["the Apple Software", "is_a", "the Apple Software"], ["the Apple Software", "is_a", "the Apple Software"], ["Apple", "is_a", "Apple"], ["C. Volume", "is_a", "Maintenance License"], ["one", "limits", "up to two"], ["1", "limits", "2"], ["Mac \nComputer", "is_a", "Mac Computer"], ["Mac Computer", "is_a", "Mac Computer"], ["Mac Computer", "is_a", "Mac Computer"], ["Mac Computer", "is_a", "Mac \nComputer"]]}, {"text": "computers you own or control.  Except as agreed to in writing by Apple[ENT0:ORG], all other terms and conditions \nof this License[ENT1:ORG] shall apply to your use of the Apple Software[ENT2:ORG] obtained under a volume or maintenance \nlicense.\nD. System Requirements[ENT3:ORG]; Apple Account[ENT4:ORG]. Please note that the Apple Software[ENT5:ORG] is supported on only Apple[ENT6:ORG]-branded hardware that meets speciﬁed system requirements as indicated by Apple[ENT7:ORG]. In addition, \nuse of and access to certain features of the Apple Software[ENT8:ORG] and certain Services (as deﬁned in Section \n6[ENT9:CARDINAL]) may require you to apply for a unique user name and password combination, known as an Apple[ENT10:ORG] \nAccount.\nE. Fonts[ENT11:PERSON]. Subject to the terms and conditions of this License[ENT12:ORG], you may use the fonts included with the \nApple Software[ENT13:ORG] to display and print content while running the Apple Software[ENT14:ORG]; however, you may only \nembed fonts in content if that is permitted by the embedding restrictions accompanying the font in \nquestion. These embedding restrictions can be found in the Font Book/Preview/Show Font Info[ENT15:EVENT] panel.\nF. Voices[ENT16:PERSON]; Live Captions[ENT17:ORG]. Subject to the terms and conditions of this License[ENT18:ORG], you may: (i) use the system \nvoices included in the Apple Software[ENT19:ORG] (“System Voices[ENT20:WORK_OF_ART]”) (1[ENT21:CARDINAL]) while running the Apple Software[ENT22:ORG] and (2[ENT23:CARDINAL]) to \ncreate your own original content and projects for your personal, non-commercial use; (ii) use the Live \nCaptions[ENT24:ORG] automatically generated on-device in real time by the Apple Software[ENT25:ORG] (“Live Captions”), \nwhether generated during a FaceTime[ENT26:PRODUCT] call or otherwise, only for your personal, non-commercial use; and \n(iii) use the Personal Voice[ENT27:ORG] feature to create a voice on device that sounds like you (“Personal Voice[ENT28:ORG]”) \nusing your own personal voice for your personal, non-commercial use. No other creation or use of the \nSystem Voices[ENT29:FAC], Live Captions[ENT30:ORG] or Personal Voice[ENT31:ORG] is permitted by this License[ENT32:ORG], including but not limited to \nthe use, reproduction, display, performance, recording, publishing or redistribution of any of the System", "entities": [["Apple", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["D. System Requirements", "ORG"], ["Apple Account", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["6", "CARDINAL"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["E. Fonts", "PERSON"], ["License", "ORG"], ["the \nApple Software", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Font Book/Preview/Show Font Info", "EVENT"], ["F. Voices", "PERSON"], ["Live Captions", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["System Voices", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["1", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["2", "CARDINAL"], ["the Live \nCaptions", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["FaceTime", "PRODUCT"], ["Personal Voice", "ORG"], ["Personal Voice", "ORG"], ["System Voices", "FAC"], ["Live Captions", "ORG"], ["Personal Voice", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"]], "relations": [["Apple", "agrees_to", "License"], ["License", "applies_to", "the Apple Software"], ["the Apple Software", "obtained_under", "Apple"], ["D. System Requirements", "requires", "Apple Account"], ["Apple Account", "associated_with", "Apple"], ["the Apple Software", "includes", "the \nApple Software"], ["License", "subject_to", "License"], ["F. Voices", "uses", "the Live \nCaptions"], ["the Apple Software", "while_running", "the Apple Software"], ["the Live \nCaptions", "generated_by", "the Apple Software"], ["Personal Voice", "sounds_like", "Personal Voice"], ["Live Captions", "permitted_by", "License"]]}, {"text": "the use, reproduction, display, performance, recording, publishing or redistribution of any of the System \nVoices, Live Captions or[ENT0:ORG] Personal Voice[ENT1:ORG] in a proﬁt, non-proﬁt[ENT2:NORP], public sharing or commercial context.\nG. Photos App Features and Support[ENT3:PERSON]. The Photos application of the Apple Software[ENT4:ORG] (“Photos App[ENT5:WORK_OF_ART]”) may \nnot support some video and photo formats. Use of some features of the Photos App will depend on the \nfeatures of your camera. Synchronizing photos with the Photos App and any Apple[ENT6:ORG] or third[ENT7:ORDINAL] party \nservices may result in loss of data. The slideshow graphics, music and themes included with the Photos \nApp are only for personal, non-commercial use in slideshows you create using the Photos App. You may \nnot use, extract or distribute, commercially or otherwise, on a standalone basis, any photographs, \nimages, graphics, artwork, audio, video or similar assets (“Digital Materials”[ENT8:ORG]) contained within, or \nprovided as a part of, the Photos App, or otherwise use the Digital Materials[ENT9:ORG] outside the context of its \nintended use as part of the Photos App.\nH. Content Caching Features[ENT10:ORG].\n1[ENT11:CARDINAL].  To the extent that Apple[ENT12:ORG] and/or its aﬃliates make particular software and/or content available for \ncaching (e.g., applicable content from the Mac App Store[ENT13:LAW]) (“Apple Eligible Content”), certain features of \nthe Apple Software[ENT14:ORG] (the “Content Caching Features”) may automatically download and locally cache \nsuch Apple Eligible Content[ENT15:ORG] on your Apple[ENT16:ORG]-branded computer that is running the Apple Software[ENT17:ORG] (for \npurposes of this Section, such Apple[ENT18:ORG]-branded computer is referred to as the “Caching Enabled Mac”).  \nBy using the Content Caching Features of[ENT19:LAW] the Apple Software[ENT20:ORG], you agree that Apple[ENT21:ORG] may \ndownload and cache such Apple Eligible Content on your Caching Enabled Mac[ENT22:ORG].  You can turn oﬀ \nthe Content Caching Features of[ENT23:LAW] the Apple Software[ENT24:ORG] at any time by going to Sharing under System \nSettings on your Caching Enabled Mac[ENT25:ORG].", "entities": [["the System \nVoices, Live Captions or", "ORG"], ["Personal Voice", "ORG"], ["non-proﬁt", "NORP"], ["G. Photos App Features and Support", "PERSON"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Photos App", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["Digital Materials”", "ORG"], ["Digital Materials", "ORG"], ["H. Content Caching Features", "ORG"], ["1", "CARDINAL"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Mac App Store", "LAW"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple Eligible Content", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Content Caching Features of", "LAW"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Caching Enabled Mac", "ORG"], ["the Content Caching Features of", "LAW"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Caching Enabled Mac", "ORG"]], "relations": [["the System \nVoices, Live Captions or", "related_to", "Personal Voice"], ["G. Photos App Features and Support", "part_of", "the Apple Software"], ["the Apple Software", "related_to", "Apple"], ["the Apple Software", "contains", "Digital Materials”"], ["H. Content Caching Features", "related_to", "Apple"], ["Apple", "part_of", "the Apple Software"], ["Apple", "related_to", "Apple"], ["the Apple Software", "part_of", "the Apple Software"], ["Apple Eligible Content", "part_of", "the Apple Software"], ["the Content Caching Features of", "related_to", "Apple"], ["Apple", "related_to", "Caching Enabled Mac"], ["Caching Enabled Mac", "part_of", "Caching Enabled Mac"]]}, {"text": "the Content Caching Features of the Apple Software[ENT0:LAW] at any time by going to Sharing under System \nSettings on your Caching Enabled Mac[ENT1:ORG].\n2[ENT2:CARDINAL].  The Content Caching Features of[ENT3:LAW] the Apple Software[ENT4:ORG] are for use only on a Caching Enabled Mac you \nown or control and solely for purposes of expediting the delivery of such Apple Eligible Content[ENT5:ORG] to \nauthorized end users within your home, company or organization.  You understand that such users may \nneed to separately authenticate with Apple[ENT6:ORG] prior to receiving the Apple Eligible Content[ENT7:ORG] and that the \nexpedited delivery of Apple Eligible Content[ENT8:ORG] through the use of your Caching Enabled Mac[ENT9:ORG] will not \nmodify the terms under which you or your end users receive such Apple Eligible Content[ENT10:ORG]. \n3[ENT11:CARDINAL].  You acknowledge and agree that all use of the Apple Eligible Content[ENT12:ORG] is subject to the applicable \nlicense terms that govern the type of Apple Eligible Content[ENT13:ORG] being cached.  These terms may include, \nbut are not limited to, the Apple Media Services Terms and Conditions[ENT14:ORG], the iCloud Terms and Conditions[ENT15:ORG], the iTunes U Instructor Agreement, the iTunes U Software License Agreement[ENT16:ORG], and/or the \napplicable licensing terms that accompanied the software being downloaded, unless the download was \naccompanied by its own separate license agreement in which case the latter would apply.  A list of \nApple Software License Agreements[ENT17:ORG] (SLAs) may be found here: https://www.apple.com/legal/sla/.[ENT18:PERSON]  You \nacknowledge and agree that the use of the Content Caching Features[ENT19:LAW] and storage of Apple Eligible \nContent[ENT20:ORG] on your Caching Enabled Mac[ENT21:ORG] does not transfer to you any rights beyond those granted to you \nin the applicable license terms for the Apple Eligible Content[ENT22:ORG] and shall not constitute a grant, waiver, or \nother limitation of any rights of Apple[ENT23:ORG] or any other copyright owners in any Apple Eligible Content[ENT24:ORG].\n4[ENT25:CARDINAL].  You are not authorized to deploy your Caching Enabled Mac[ENT26:ORG] with the Content Caching Features[ENT27:LAW]", "entities": [["the Content Caching Features of the Apple Software", "LAW"], ["Caching Enabled Mac", "ORG"], ["2", "CARDINAL"], ["The Content Caching Features of", "LAW"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple Eligible Content", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Eligible Content", "ORG"], ["Apple Eligible Content", "ORG"], ["Caching Enabled Mac", "ORG"], ["Apple Eligible Content", "ORG"], ["3", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Eligible Content", "ORG"], ["Apple Eligible Content", "ORG"], ["the Apple Media Services Terms and Conditions", "ORG"], ["the iCloud Terms and Conditions", "ORG"], ["the iTunes U Software License Agreement", "ORG"], ["Apple Software License Agreements", "ORG"], ["https://www.apple.com/legal/sla/.", "PERSON"], ["the Content Caching Features", "LAW"], ["Apple Eligible \nContent", "ORG"], ["Caching Enabled Mac", "ORG"], ["the Apple Eligible Content", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Eligible Content", "ORG"], ["4", "CARDINAL"], ["Caching Enabled Mac", "ORG"], ["the Content Caching Features", "LAW"]], "relations": [["the Content Caching Features of the Apple Software", "is_part_of", "Caching Enabled Mac"], ["The Content Caching Features of", "is_part_of", "the Apple Software"], ["Apple Eligible Content", "requires_authentication", "Apple"], ["the Apple Eligible Content", "is_subject_to", "Apple Eligible Content"], ["the Apple Media Services Terms and Conditions", "is_related_to", "the iCloud Terms and Conditions"], ["Apple Software License Agreements", "is_found_at", "https://www.apple.com/legal/sla/."], ["the Content Caching Features", "uses", "Caching Enabled Mac"], ["Apple Eligible \nContent", "is_subject_to", "the Apple Eligible Content"], ["Apple", "holds_rights_over", "Apple Eligible Content"], ["Caching Enabled Mac", "uses", "the Content Caching Features"]]}, {"text": "other limitation of any rights of Apple[ENT0:ORG] or any other copyright owners in any Apple Eligible Content[ENT1:ORG].\n4[ENT2:CARDINAL].  You are not authorized to deploy your Caching Enabled Mac[ENT3:ORG] with the Content Caching Features[ENT4:LAW] \nenabled on a network you do not own or control (or which you are not legally authorized to use for such \npurposes), or to permit access to such Apple Eligible Content[ENT5:ORG] from end users outside of your home, \ncompany or organization.  You agree to only use the Content Caching Features[ENT6:LAW] for your own personal, \nnon-commercial use or for internal use within your company or organization, and only as expressly \npermitted herein.  You may not provide a service to third[ENT7:ORDINAL] parties that integrates with or leverages \nservices or information provided by the Content Caching Features[ENT8:LAW] or uses the Content Caching Features[ENT9:LAW] \nin any way.\n5[ENT10:CARDINAL].  By enabling the Content Caching Features of[ENT11:LAW] the Apple Software[ENT12:ORG], you agree that Apple[ENT13:ORG] may store, \nmonitor, and secure the Apple Eligible Content[ENT14:ORG] on your Caching Enabled Mac[ENT15:ORG], and may collect and use \ntechnical information about your Caching Enabled Mac[ENT16:ORG] and related networks, including but not limited \nto, hardware identiﬁers and IP[ENT17:ORG] addresses, for such purposes.  You agree not to disable, disrupt, hack, \ncircumvent, or otherwise interfere with Apple[ENT18:ORG]’s veriﬁcation, storage or authentication mechanisms, digital \nsigning, digital rights management, or other security mechanisms implemented in or by the Apple \nSoftware[ENT19:ORG], services, the Apple Eligible Content[ENT20:ORG], or other Apple[ENT21:ORG] software or technology, or to enable \nothers to do so.  \n6[ENT22:CARDINAL].  Apple[ENT23:ORG] reserves the right to stop making Apple Eligible Content[ENT24:ORG] available for caching on your Caching \nEnabled Mac[ENT25:ORG] (e.g., some content that you may have previously cached may not be available for \nsubsequent caching) and to remove any cached Apple[ENT26:ORG] Eligible Content from your Caching Enabled \nMacs[ENT27:ORG] at any time in its sole discretion, and Apple[ENT28:ORG] shall have no liability to you in such event.  You", "entities": [["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Eligible Content", "ORG"], ["4", "CARDINAL"], ["Caching Enabled Mac", "ORG"], ["the Content Caching Features", "LAW"], ["Apple Eligible Content", "ORG"], ["the Content Caching Features", "LAW"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["the Content Caching Features", "LAW"], ["the Content Caching Features", "LAW"], ["5", "CARDINAL"], ["the Content Caching Features of", "LAW"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Eligible Content", "ORG"], ["Caching Enabled Mac", "ORG"], ["Caching Enabled Mac", "ORG"], ["IP", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple \nSoftware", "ORG"], ["the Apple Eligible Content", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["6", "CARDINAL"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Eligible Content", "ORG"], ["Caching \nEnabled Mac", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Caching Enabled \nMacs", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"]], "relations": [["Apple", "has_rights", "Apple Eligible Content"], ["Caching Enabled Mac", "uses_feature", "the Content Caching Features"], ["Apple Eligible Content", "related_to", "Apple Eligible Content"], ["the Content Caching Features of", "part_of", "the Apple Software"], ["the Apple Software", "developed_by", "Apple"], ["Apple", "manages_content", "the Apple Eligible Content"], ["Caching Enabled Mac", "uses_device", "Caching Enabled Mac"], ["Apple", "implements", "the Apple \nSoftware"], ["Apple", "controls_content", "Apple Eligible Content"], ["Caching \nEnabled Mac", "related_to", "Apple"]]}, {"text": "subsequent caching) and to remove any cached Apple[ENT0:ORG] Eligible Content from your Caching Enabled \nMacs[ENT1:ORG] at any time in its sole discretion, and Apple[ENT2:ORG] shall have no liability to you in such event.  You \nunderstand that such caching of Apple Eligible Content[ENT3:ORG] may not be available in all countries or regions.  \nYou may remove the cached Apple Eligible Content[ENT4:ORG] and disable the Content Caching Features[ENT5:LAW] at any \ntime.\nI. Remote Desktop Connections[ENT6:ORG].  Subject to the terms and conditions of this License[ENT7:ORG], when remotely \nconnecting from another computer or electronic device (each a “Device”) to an Apple[ENT8:ORG]-branded computer \nthat is running the Apple Software[ENT9:ORG] (for purposes of this Section, such Apple[ENT10:ORG]-branded computer is \nreferred to as the “Home Mac[ENT11:ORG]”), whether through the Screen Sharing feature or through any other \nmeans:\n(i) only one[ENT12:CARDINAL] (1[ENT13:CARDINAL]) Device may remotely connect at any one[ENT14:CARDINAL] time, whether directly or indirectly, to \ncontrol the graphical desktop session of the Apple Software[ENT15:ORG] that is running and being displayed \non the Home Mac[ENT16:ORG]; and\n(ii) a reasonable number of Devices may remotely connect at the same time for the sole purpose \nof simultaneously observing the same graphical desktop session of the Apple Software[ENT17:ORG] that is \nrunning and being displayed on the Home Mac[ENT18:ORG], as long as they do not control the Apple \nSoftware[ENT19:ORG] in any way; but\n(iii) only one[ENT20:CARDINAL] (1[ENT21:CARDINAL]) Apple[ENT22:ORG]-branded Device may remotely connect at any one[ENT23:CARDINAL] time, whether directly or \nindirectly, to control a separate graphical desktop session of the Apple Software[ENT24:ORG] that is diﬀerent from the one running and being displayed on the Home Mac[ENT25:ORG], and such connection may only be \nmade through the Screen Sharing feature of the Apple Software[ENT26:ORG].\nExcept as expressly permitted in this Section 2I[ENT27:LAW] or Section 3[ENT28:LAW], or except as otherwise licensed by Apple[ENT29:ORG], \nyou agree not to use the Apple Software[ENT30:ORG], or any of its functionality, in connection with service bureau, \ntime-sharing, terminal sharing or other similar types of services, whether such services are being", "entities": [["Apple", "ORG"], ["Caching Enabled \nMacs", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Eligible Content", "ORG"], ["Apple Eligible Content", "ORG"], ["the Content Caching Features", "LAW"], ["I. Remote Desktop Connections", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the “Home Mac", "ORG"], ["only one", "CARDINAL"], ["1", "CARDINAL"], ["one", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Home Mac", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Home Mac", "ORG"], ["Apple \nSoftware", "ORG"], ["only one", "CARDINAL"], ["1", "CARDINAL"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["one", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Home Mac", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Section 2I", "LAW"], ["Section 3", "LAW"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"]], "relations": [["Apple", "is a parent of", "Apple"], ["Caching Enabled \nMacs", "is a sibling of", "Apple"], ["Apple Eligible Content", "is a type of", "Apple"], ["Apple Eligible Content", "is related to", "the Content Caching Features"], ["I. Remote Desktop Connections", "is governed by", "License"], ["Apple", "is a type of", "the Apple Software"], ["Apple", "is a type of", "the “Home Mac"], ["only one", "is a quantity of", "1"], ["one", "is a quantity of", "only one"], ["the Apple Software", "is a type of", "the Home Mac"], ["the Apple Software", "is a type of", "the Home Mac"], ["Apple \nSoftware", "is a type of", "only one"], ["1", "is a type of", "Apple"], ["one", "is a type of", "the Apple Software"], ["the Home Mac", "is a type of", "the Apple Software"], ["Section 2I", "is a section of", "Section 3"], ["Apple", "is a type of", "the Apple Software"]]}, {"text": "time-sharing, terminal sharing or other similar types of services, whether such services are being \nprovided within your own organization or to third[ENT0:ORDINAL] parties.\nJ. Other Use Restrictions[ENT1:ORG]. The grants set forth in this License[ENT2:ORG] do not permit you to, and you agree not to, \ninstall, use or run the Apple Software[ENT3:ORG] on any non-Apple[ENT4:ORG]-branded computer, or to enable others to do so. \nYou agree not to remove, obscure, or alter any proprietary notices (including trademark and copyright \nnotices) that may be aﬃxed to or contained within the Apple Software[ENT5:ORG]. Except as otherwise permitted by \nthe terms of this License or otherwise licensed by Apple[ENT6:ORG]: (i) only one[ENT7:CARDINAL] user may use the Apple Software[ENT8:ORG] at \na time, and (ii) you may not make the Apple Software[ENT9:ORG] available over a network where it could be run or \nused by multiple computers at the same time. Except as expressly permitted in Section 3[ENT10:LAW], you may not \nrent, lease, lend, sell, redistribute or sublicense the Apple Software[ENT11:ORG].\nK. Backup Copy[ENT12:PERSON]. You may make one[ENT13:CARDINAL] copy of the Apple Software[ENT14:ORG] (excluding the Boot ROM code and \nother Apple[ENT15:ORG] ﬁrmware that is embedded or otherwise contained in Apple[ENT16:ORG]-branded hardware) in machine-[ENT17:DATE]\nreadable form for backup purposes only; provided that the backup copy must include all copyright or \nother proprietary notices contained on the original. Apple Boot ROM[ENT18:PERSON] code and ﬁrmware is provided only \nfor use on Apple[ENT19:ORG]-branded hardware and you may not copy, modify or redistribute the Apple Boot ROM \ncode or ﬁrmware, or any portions thereof.\nL. Migration of Existing Software[ENT20:ORG]. If you use Setup/Migration Assistant to transfer software from one[ENT21:CARDINAL] \nApple[ENT22:ORG]-branded computer to another Apple[ENT23:ORG]-branded computer, please remember that continued use of \nthe original copy of the software may be prohibited once a copy has been transferred to another \ncomputer, unless you already have a licensed copy of such software on both computers. You should \ncheck the relevant software license agreements for applicable terms and conditions. Third[ENT24:ORDINAL] party", "entities": [["third", "ORDINAL"], ["J. Other Use Restrictions", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["non-Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["only one", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Section 3", "LAW"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["K. Backup Copy", "PERSON"], ["one", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["machine-", "DATE"], ["Apple Boot ROM", "PERSON"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["L. Migration of Existing Software", "ORG"], ["one", "CARDINAL"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Third", "ORDINAL"]], "relations": [["J. Other Use Restrictions", "License", "License"], ["the Apple Software", "Brand", "non-Apple"], ["the Apple Software", "Brand", "Apple"], ["the Apple Software", "Software", "the Apple Software"], ["K. Backup Copy", "Backup", "the Apple Software"], ["Apple Boot ROM", "Brand", "Apple"], ["L. Migration of Existing Software", "Migration", "Apple"], ["Apple", "Brand", "Apple"]]}, {"text": "computer, unless you already have a licensed copy of such software on both computers. You should \ncheck the relevant software license agreements for applicable terms and conditions. Third[ENT0:ORDINAL] party \nsoftware and services may not be compatible with this Apple Software[ENT1:ORG] and installation of this Apple \nSoftware[ENT2:ORG] may aﬀect the availability and usability of such third[ENT3:ORDINAL] party software or services.\nM. Open Source[ENT4:ORG]. Certain components of the Apple Software[ENT5:ORG], and third[ENT6:ORDINAL] party open source programs \nincluded with the Apple Software[ENT7:ORG], have been or may be made available by Apple[ENT8:ORG] on its Open Source[ENT9:WORK_OF_ART] \nweb site (https://www.opensource.apple.com/) (collectively the “Open-Sourced Components[ENT10:EVENT]”). You may \nmodify or replace only these Open-Sourced Components[ENT11:ORG]; provided that: (i) the resultant modiﬁed Apple \nSoftware[ENT12:ORG] is used, in place of the unmodiﬁed Apple Software[ENT13:ORG], on Apple[ENT14:ORG]-branded computers you own or \ncontrol, as long as each such Apple[ENT15:ORG] computer has a properly licensed copy of the Apple Software[ENT16:ORG] on it; \nand (ii) you otherwise comply with the terms of this License[ENT17:ORG] and any applicable licensing terms \ngoverning use of the Open-Sourced Components[ENT18:ORG]. Apple[ENT19:ORG] is not obligated to provide any updates, \nmaintenance, warranty, technical or other support, or services for the resultant modiﬁed Apple Software[ENT20:ORG]. \nYou expressly acknowledge that if failure or damage to Apple[ENT21:ORG] hardware results from modiﬁcation of the \nOpen-Sourced Components of the Apple Software[ENT22:ORG], such failure or damage is excluded from the terms of \nthe Apple[ENT23:ORG] hardware warranty.\nN. No Reverse Engineering[ENT24:ORG]. You may not, and you agree not to or enable others to, copy (except as \nexpressly permitted by this License[ENT25:PERSON] or by the Usage Rules[ENT26:ORG] if they are applicable to you), decompile, \nreverse engineer, disassemble, attempt to derive the source code of, decrypt, modify, or create \nderivative works of the Apple Software[ENT27:ORG] or any services provided by the Apple Software[ENT28:ORG] or any part", "entities": [["Third", "ORDINAL"], ["this Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple \nSoftware", "ORG"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["M. Open Source", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Open Source", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["the “Open-Sourced Components", "EVENT"], ["these Open-Sourced Components", "ORG"], ["Apple \nSoftware", "ORG"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"], ["the Open-Sourced Components", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["N. No Reverse Engineering", "ORG"], ["License", "PERSON"], ["the Usage Rules", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"]], "relations": [["this Apple Software", "is_a", "Apple \nSoftware"], ["M. Open Source", "is_a", "the Apple Software"], ["third", "is_a", "the Apple Software"], ["Apple", "is_a", "Open Source"], ["the “Open-Sourced Components", "is_a", "these Open-Sourced Components"], ["Apple \nSoftware", "is_a", "Apple Software"], ["Apple", "is_a", "Apple"], ["the Apple Software", "is_a", "License"], ["the Open-Sourced Components", "is_a", "Apple"], ["Apple Software", "is_a", "Apple"], ["the Apple Software", "is_a", "Apple"], ["N. No Reverse Engineering", "is_a", "License"], ["the Usage Rules", "is_a", "the Apple Software"]]}, {"text": "reverse engineer, disassemble, attempt to derive the source code of, decrypt, modify, or create \nderivative works of the Apple Software[ENT0:ORG] or any services provided by the Apple Software[ENT1:ORG] or any part \nthereof (except as and only to the extent any foregoing restriction is prohibited by applicable law or by \nlicensing terms governing use of Open-Sourced Components[ENT2:ORG] that may be included with the Apple[ENT3:ORG] \nSoftware).O. Compliance with Laws. You agree to use the Apple Software[ENT4:ORG] and the Services (as deﬁned in Section \n6[ENT5:CARDINAL] below) in compliance with all applicable laws, including local laws of the country or region in which you \nreside or in which you download or use the Apple Software and Services[ENT6:ORG]. Features of the Apple \nSoftware[ENT7:ORG] and the Services may not be available in all languages or regions, and some features may vary \nby region. An Internet connection is required for some features of the Apple Software and Services[ENT8:ORG].\nP. Third Party Software[ENT9:ORG]. Apple[ENT10:ORG] has provided as part of the Apple Software[ENT11:ORG] package, and may provide as \nan upgrade, update or supplement to the Apple Software[ENT12:ORG], access to certain third[ENT13:ORDINAL] party software or \nservices as a convenience. To the extent that the Apple Software[ENT14:ORG] contains or provides access to any \nthird[ENT15:ORDINAL] party software or services, Apple[ENT16:ORG] has no express or implied obligation to provide any technical or \nother support for such software or services. Please contact the appropriate software vendor, \nmanufacturer or service provider directly for technical support and customer service related to its \nsoftware, service and/or products.\nQ. Apple Software Changes[ENT17:ORG]. The Apple Software[ENT18:ORG] will periodically check with Apple for Apple Software \nChanges[ENT19:ORG]. If a change is available, the change may automatically download and install onto your \ncomputer and, if applicable, your peripheral devices. By using the Apple Software[ENT20:ORG], you agree that \nApple[ENT21:ORG] may download and install automatic Apple Software Changes[ENT22:ORG] onto your computer and your", "entities": [["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Open-Sourced Components", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["6", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["the Apple \nSoftware", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["P. Third Party Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Q. Apple Software Changes", "ORG"], ["The Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple for Apple Software \nChanges", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Software Changes", "ORG"]], "relations": [["the Apple Software", "provides", "the Apple Software"], ["the Apple Software", "includes", "Open-Sourced Components"], ["Apple", "is_part_of", "the Apple Software"], ["the Apple Software", "governs", "6"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "is_related_to", "the Apple \nSoftware"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "provides_access_to", "P. Third Party Software"], ["Apple", "is_part_of", "Apple Software"], ["the Apple Software", "contains", "third"], ["the Apple Software", "provides", "third"], ["Apple", "is_related_to", "Q. Apple Software Changes"], ["The Apple Software", "checks_for", "Apple for Apple Software \nChanges"], ["the Apple Software", "may_download", "Apple"]]}, {"text": "computer and, if applicable, your peripheral devices. By using the Apple Software[ENT0:ORG], you agree that \nApple[ENT1:ORG] may download and install automatic Apple Software Changes[ENT2:ORG] onto your computer and your \nperipheral devices. You can turn oﬀ automatic operating system updates and Rapid Security[ENT3:ORG] \nResponses at any time by adjusting the settings found within System Settings > Software Update[ENT4:ORG] > \nAdvanced.\nR. System Characters. Subject to the terms and conditions of this License[ENT5:ORG], you may use the Memoji[ENT6:PERSON] \ncharacters included in or created with the Apple Software[ENT7:ORG] (“System Characters[ENT8:WORK_OF_ART]”): (i) while running the \nApple Software[ENT9:ORG]; and (ii) to create your own original content and projects for your personal, non-\ncommercial use. No other use of the System Characters is permitted by this License[ENT10:ORG], including but not \nlimited to the use, reproduction, display, performance, recording, publishing or redistribution of any of \nthe System Characters in a proﬁt, non-proﬁt[ENT11:NORP], public sharing or commercial context.\n3[ENT12:CARDINAL]. Leasing for Permitted Developer Services.\nA. Leasing.  You may lease or sublease a validly licensed version of the Apple Software[ENT13:ORG] in its entirety to \nan individual or organization (each, a “Lessee[ENT14:WORK_OF_ART]”) provided that all of the following conditions are met: \n(i) the leased Apple Software[ENT15:ORG] must be used for the sole purpose of providing Permitted \nDeveloper Services[ENT16:ORG] and each Lessee[ENT17:PERSON] must review and agree to be bound by the terms of this \nLicense;\n(ii) each lease period must be for a minimum period of twenty-four[ENT18:CARDINAL] (24) consecutive hours[ENT19:TIME]; \n(iii) during the lease period, the End User Lessee must have sole and exclusive use and control \nof the Apple Software[ENT20:ORG] and the Apple[ENT21:ORG]-branded hardware on which it is installed, except that you, \nas the party leasing the Apple Software[ENT22:ORG] (“Lessor[ENT23:WORK_OF_ART]”), may provide administrative support for the \nApple Software[ENT24:ORG]; and \n(iv) prior to using the Apple Software[ENT25:ORG], the End User Lessee must review and agree to be bound", "entities": [["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Software Changes", "ORG"], ["Rapid Security", "ORG"], ["System Settings > Software Update", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"], ["Memoji", "PERSON"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["System Characters", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"], ["non-proﬁt", "NORP"], ["3", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Lessee", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Permitted \nDeveloper Services", "ORG"], ["Lessee", "PERSON"], ["twenty-four", "CARDINAL"], ["24) consecutive hours", "TIME"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Lessor", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"]], "relations": [["the Apple Software", "developed_by", "Apple"], ["Apple", "provides", "Apple Software Changes"], ["Apple Software Changes", "related_to", "Rapid Security"], ["License", "uses", "the Apple Software"], ["the Apple Software", "includes", "Apple Software"], ["License", "restricts", "non-proﬁt"], ["the Apple Software", "leases", "Apple Software"], ["Apple Software", "provides", "Permitted \nDeveloper Services"], ["the Apple Software", "installed_on", "Apple"], ["the Apple Software", "is", "Lessor"]]}, {"text": "Apple Software[ENT0:ORG]; and \n(iv) prior to using the Apple Software[ENT1:ORG], the End User Lessee must review and agree to be bound \nby the terms applicable to any software preinstalled on the Apple Software[ENT2:ORG], including, but not \nlimited to Apple[ENT3:ORG]’s Xcode[ENT4:ORG] developer software and any other Apple[ENT5:ORG] or third[ENT6:ORDINAL]-party software.\nFor purposes of this Section 3[ENT7:LAW]: (A) End User Lessee means a Lessee[ENT8:PERSON] who is the end user ultimately \nusing the leased Apple Software[ENT9:ORG] solely for Permitted Developer Services[ENT10:ORG]; and (B) Permitted Developer \nServices means continuous integration services, including but not limited to software development, \nbuilding software from source, automated testing during software development, and running necessary developer tools to support such activities. Each Lessor must provide Apple[ENT11:ORG] with advance notice prior to \nleasing or subleasing the Apple Software[ENT12:ORG] pursuant to this Section 3[ENT13:LAW] by contacting Apple[ENT14:ORG] Developer \nRelations (https://developer.apple.com/contact/macos-license/).\nB. Subleasing[ENT15:PERSON].  A Lessee[ENT16:PERSON] may further sublease the Apple Software[ENT17:ORG] pursuant to this Section 3[ENT18:LAW] provided \nthat such Lessee[ENT19:PERSON] complies with all of the terms of this Section 3[ENT20:LAW]. A Lessee[ENT21:PERSON] subleasing the Apple \nSoftware[ENT22:ORG] (who shall also be considered a Lessor under this Section 3[ENT23:LAW]) must fully relinquish exclusive use \nand control of the Apple Software[ENT24:ORG] and the Apple[ENT25:ORG]-branded hardware on which it is installed to its Lessee[ENT26:PERSON] \nduring the lease period.\nC. Enforcement[ENT27:ORG]. As a Lessor, you shall be responsible for: (i) ensuring that each Lessee[ENT28:PERSON] complies with \nthe requirements of this Section 3[ENT29:LAW]; (ii) ensuring each Lessee[ENT30:PERSON] agrees to all applicable license terms; and \n(iii) assisting Apple[ENT31:ORG] in enforcing compliance therewith. If a Lessee[ENT32:PERSON] breaches this License[ENT33:PERSON] or other \napplicable Apple[ENT34:ORG] license terms, their rights to use the Apple Software[ENT35:ORG] shall automatically terminate and \nyou agree to immediately terminate such Lessee[ENT36:PERSON]’s use of the Apple Software[ENT37:ORG] upon your discovery of \nsuch breach or upon written notice from Apple[ENT38:ORG] of such breach.", "entities": [["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Xcode", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["Section 3", "LAW"], ["Lessee", "PERSON"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Permitted Developer Services", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Section 3", "LAW"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["B. Subleasing", "PERSON"], ["Lessee", "PERSON"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Section 3", "LAW"], ["Lessee", "PERSON"], ["Section 3", "LAW"], ["Lessee", "PERSON"], ["Apple \nSoftware", "ORG"], ["Section 3", "LAW"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Lessee", "PERSON"], ["C. Enforcement", "ORG"], ["Lessee", "PERSON"], ["Section 3", "LAW"], ["Lessee", "PERSON"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Lessee", "PERSON"], ["License", "PERSON"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Lessee", "PERSON"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"]], "relations": [["Apple Software", "uses", "the Apple Software"], ["the Apple Software", "is_preinstalled_on", "the Apple Software"], ["Apple", "has_software", "Xcode"], ["Apple", "has_software", "Apple"], ["Section 3", "defines", "Lessee"], ["Apple Software", "is_for", "Permitted Developer Services"], ["Apple", "provides_notice_to", "Apple Software"], ["B. Subleasing", "may_sublease", "Lessee"], ["Lessee", "complies_with", "Section 3"], ["Lessee", "subleases", "Apple \nSoftware"], ["Section 3", "relinquishes_control_of", "the Apple Software"], ["C. Enforcement", "is_responsible_for", "Lessee"], ["Lessee", "assists_in_enforcing", "Apple"], ["Lessee", "breaches", "License"], ["Apple", "terminates_use_of", "Apple Software"], ["Apple", "notifies_of_breach", "Lessee"]]}, {"text": "you agree to immediately terminate such Lessee[ENT0:PERSON]’s use of the Apple Software[ENT1:ORG] upon your discovery of \nsuch breach or upon written notice from Apple[ENT2:ORG] of such breach.  \nD. Virtualization.  For each copy of the Apple Software[ENT3:ORG] subject to a lease under this Section 3[ENT4:LAW], either a \nLessor or a Lessee[ENT5:PERSON] (but not both) may install, use and run additional copies or instances of the Apple[ENT6:ORG] \nSoftware within virtual operating system environments in accordance with Section 2B(iii[ENT7:LAW]), provided that a \nLessor may only virtualize a single instance or copy of the Apple Software[ENT8:ORG] as a provisioning tool for the \npurpose of providing a Lessee[ENT9:PERSON] with access to and use of the Apple Software[ENT10:ORG] pursuant to this Section 3[ENT11:LAW]. \nE. System Conﬁguration[ENT12:ORG]. If you are a Lessee[ENT13:PERSON], you acknowledge that the Apple Software[ENT14:ORG] may have been \npreviously conﬁgured by the Lessor[ENT15:PERSON] who is leasing the Apple Software[ENT16:ORG] to you, including the selection of \nsettings for Analytics, Location Services[ENT17:ORG], and other security, privacy and data collection-related features. \nYou acknowledge and agree that Apple[ENT18:ORG] is not responsible for the conﬁguration of the Apple Software[ENT19:ORG] by \nthe Lessor.\n4[ENT20:CARDINAL]. Transfer.\nA. If you obtained the Apple Software[ENT21:ORG] preinstalled on Apple[ENT22:ORG]-branded hardware or if you obtained your \nlicense to the Apple Software[ENT23:ORG] from the Mac App Store[ENT24:WORK_OF_ART] or through a software update, you may make a \none[ENT25:CARDINAL]-time permanent transfer of all of your license rights to the Apple Software[ENT26:ORG] (in its original form as \nprovided by Apple[ENT27:ORG]) to another party, provided that: (i) the Apple Software[ENT28:ORG] is transferred together with \nyour Apple[ENT29:ORG]-branded hardware; (ii) the transfer must include all of the Apple Software[ENT30:ORG], including all its \ncomponent parts and this License; (iii) you do not retain any copies of the Apple Software[ENT31:ORG], full or partial, \nincluding copies stored on a computer or other storage device; and (iv) the party receiving the Apple[ENT32:ORG] \nSoftware reads and agrees to accept the terms and conditions of this License[ENT33:ORG]. For purposes of this", "entities": [["Lessee", "PERSON"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Section 3", "LAW"], ["Lessee", "PERSON"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Section 2B(iii", "LAW"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Lessee", "PERSON"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Section 3", "LAW"], ["E. System Conﬁguration", "ORG"], ["Lessee", "PERSON"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Lessor", "PERSON"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Location Services", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["4", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Mac App Store", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["one", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"]], "relations": [["Lessee", "uses", "the Apple Software"], ["Apple", "provides", "the Apple Software"], ["Lessee", "leases", "the Apple Software"], ["Lessee", "accesses", "the Apple Software"], ["Lessee", "acknowledges", "Lessor"], ["Lessor", "leases", "the Apple Software"], ["Apple", "is responsible for", "the Apple Software"], ["the Apple Software", "obtains", "the Apple Software"], ["Apple", "is branded with", "the Apple Software"], ["Apple", "is provided by", "the Apple Software"], ["Apple", "is branded with", "the Apple Software"]]}, {"text": "Software reads and agrees to accept the terms and conditions of this License[ENT0:ORG]. For purposes of this \nLicense, if Apple[ENT1:ORG] provides an update (e.g., version 10.14[ENT2:CARDINAL] to 10.14.1) to the Apple Software[ENT3:ORG], the update is \nconsidered part of the Apple Software[ENT4:ORG] and may not be transferred separately from the pre-update \nversion of the Apple Software[ENT5:ORG].\nB. You may not transfer any Apple Software[ENT6:ORG] that has been modiﬁed or replaced under Section 2M[ENT7:LAW] \nabove. All components of the Apple Software[ENT8:ORG] are provided as part of a bundle and may not be \nseparated from the bundle and distributed as standalone applications. Note that the Apple Software[ENT9:ORG] \nprovided with a particular Apple[ENT10:ORG]-branded hardware product might not run on other models of Apple-\nbranded hardware.\nC. Any copy of the Apple Software[ENT11:ORG] that may be provided by Apple[ENT12:ORG] for promotional, evaluation, \ndiagnostic or restorative purposes may be used only for such purposes and may not be resold or \ntransferred.D. Apple[ENT13:ORG] may assign all or any portion of this License[ENT14:PERSON] or any rights or obligations hereunder to any Apple[ENT15:ORG] \naﬃliate or subsidiary at any time without notice.\n5[ENT16:CARDINAL]. Consent to Use of Data. Certain features like Analytics, Location Services[ENT17:ORG], Siri, Dictation and \nSpotlight may require information from your computer to provide their respective functions. When you \nturn on or use these features, details will be provided regarding what information is sent to Apple[ENT18:ORG] and \nhow the information may be used.  You can learn more by visiting https://www.apple.com/privacy/. At all \ntimes your information will be treated in accordance with Apple[ENT19:ORG]’s Privacy Policy[ENT20:ORG], which can be viewed at: \nhttps://www.apple.com/legal/privacy/.\n6[ENT21:CARDINAL]. Apple Software, Services[ENT22:ORG], and Third Party Materials[ENT23:ORG].\nA. General. The Apple Software[ENT24:ORG] may enable access to Apple[ENT25:ORG]’s iTunes Store[ENT26:ORG], Mac App Store[ENT27:WORK_OF_ART], Apple \nBooks, Game Center[ENT28:ORG], iCloud[ENT29:ORG], Maps, News and other Apple[ENT30:ORG] and third[ENT31:ORDINAL] party services and web sites", "entities": [["License", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["10.14", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Section 2M", "LAW"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["D. Apple", "ORG"], ["License", "PERSON"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["5", "CARDINAL"], ["Location Services", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Privacy Policy", "ORG"], ["6", "CARDINAL"], ["Apple Software, Services", "ORG"], ["Third Party Materials", "ORG"], ["The Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["iTunes Store", "ORG"], ["Mac App Store", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["Apple \nBooks, Game Center", "ORG"], ["iCloud", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["third", "ORDINAL"]], "relations": [["Apple", "provides", "the Apple Software"], ["the Apple Software", "is part of", "the Apple Software"], ["Apple", "provides", "Apple"], ["Apple", "assigns", "License"], ["Apple", "is treated in accordance with", "Apple"], ["The Apple Software", "enables access to", "Apple"]]}, {"text": "A. General. The Apple Software[ENT0:ORG] may enable access to Apple[ENT1:ORG]’s iTunes Store[ENT2:ORG], Mac App Store[ENT3:WORK_OF_ART], Apple \nBooks, Game Center[ENT4:ORG], iCloud[ENT5:ORG], Maps, News and other Apple[ENT6:ORG] and third[ENT7:ORDINAL] party services and web sites \n(collectively and individually, “Services”). Use of these Services requires Internet access and use of \ncertain Services may require an Apple Account[ENT8:ORG], may require you to accept additional terms and may be \nsubject to additional fees. By using this software in connection with an Apple Account[ENT9:ORG], or other Apple \nServices[ENT10:ORG], you agree to the applicable terms of service, such as the latest Apple Media Services[ENT11:ORG] Terms \nand Conditions for the country or region in which you access such Services, which you may access and \nreview at https://www.apple.com/legal/internet-services/itunes/.[ENT12:ORG]\nB. If you sign up for iCloud[ENT13:PERSON], certain iCloud[ENT14:PERSON] features like “iCloud Drive”, “Shared Albums[ENT15:WORK_OF_ART]” and “Find My[ENT16:WORK_OF_ART]” \nmay be accessed directly from the Apple Software[ENT17:ORG]. You acknowledge and agree that your use of iCloud[ENT18:PERSON] \nand these features is subject to the latest terms and conditions of the iCloud[ENT19:PERSON] service, which you may \naccess and review at: https://www.apple.com/legal/internet-services/icloud/.\nC. News App Content. Your use of content accessed through the News application is limited solely to \npersonal, noncommercial use, does not transfer any ownership interest to you in the content, and \nspeciﬁcally excludes, without limitation, any commercial or promotional use rights in such content.  \nD. Maps. The maps service and features of the Apple Software[ENT20:ORG] (“Maps”), including map data coverage, \nmay vary by region. When you turn on or use Maps, details will be provided regarding what information \nis sent to Apple[ENT21:ORG] and how the information may be used. You acknowledge and agree that your use of \nMaps is subject to the latest terms and conditions of the Maps service, which you may access and \nreview on the sidebar of the Maps application.", "entities": [["The Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["iTunes Store", "ORG"], ["Mac App Store", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["Apple \nBooks, Game Center", "ORG"], ["iCloud", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["Apple Account", "ORG"], ["an Apple Account", "ORG"], ["Apple \nServices", "ORG"], ["Apple Media Services", "ORG"], ["https://www.apple.com/legal/internet-services/itunes/.", "ORG"], ["iCloud", "PERSON"], ["iCloud", "PERSON"], ["Shared Albums", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["Find My", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["iCloud", "PERSON"], ["iCloud", "PERSON"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"]], "relations": [["The Apple Software", "enables access to", "Apple"], ["Apple", "has access to", "iTunes Store"], ["Apple", "has access to", "Mac App Store"], ["Apple", "has access to", "Apple \nBooks, Game Center"], ["Apple", "has access to", "iCloud"], ["Apple", "has access to", "Apple"], ["Apple Account", "requires", "an Apple Account"], ["Apple \nServices", "includes", "Apple Media Services"], ["iCloud", "has features", "iCloud"], ["iCloud", "is subject to", "iCloud"], ["the Apple Software", "provides information to", "Apple"]]}, {"text": "Maps is subject to the latest terms and conditions of the Maps service, which you may access and \nreview on the sidebar of the Maps application.\nE. You understand that by using any of the Apple Software and Services[ENT0:ORG], you may encounter content \nthat may be deemed oﬀensive, indecent, or objectionable, which content may or may not be identiﬁed \nas having explicit language, and that the results of any search or entering of a particular URL may \nautomatically and unintentionally generate links or references to objectionable material. Nevertheless, \nyou agree to use the Apple Software and Services[ENT1:ORG] at your sole risk and that Apple[ENT2:ORG], its aﬃliates, agents, \nprincipals, or licensors shall have no liability to you for content that may be found to be oﬀensive, \nindecent, or objectionable.\nF. Certain Apple Software and Services[ENT3:ORG] may display, include or make available content, data, \ninformation, applications or materials from third[ENT4:ORDINAL] parties (“Third Party Materials”) or provide links to \ncertain third[ENT5:ORDINAL] party web sites. By using the Apple Software and Services[ENT6:ORG], you acknowledge and agree \nthat Apple[ENT7:ORG] is not responsible for examining or evaluating the content, accuracy, completeness, \ntimeliness, validity, copyright compliance, legality, decency, quality or any other aspect of such Third[ENT8:ORDINAL] \nParty Materials[ENT9:ORG] or web sites. Apple[ENT10:ORG], its oﬃcers, aﬃliates and subsidiaries do not warrant or endorse and \ndo not assume and will not have any liability or responsibility to you or any other person for any third-\nparty Services[ENT11:ORG], Third Party Materials[ENT12:ORG] or web sites, or for any other materials, products, or services of \nthird[ENT13:ORDINAL] parties. Third Party Materials[ENT14:ORG] and links to other web sites are provided solely as a convenience to you.\nG. Neither Apple[ENT15:ORG] nor any of its content providers guarantees the availability, accuracy, completeness, \nreliability, or timeliness of stock information, location data, health information or any other data displayed", "entities": [["the Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["F. Certain Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Third", "ORDINAL"], ["Party Materials", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["party Services", "ORG"], ["Third Party Materials", "ORG"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["Third Party Materials", "ORG"], ["G. Neither Apple", "ORG"]], "relations": [["the Apple Software and Services", "uses", "the Apple Software and Services"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "provided_by", "Apple"], ["F. Certain Apple Software and Services", "includes", "the Apple Software and Services"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "provided_by", "Apple"], ["Party Materials", "related_to", "party Services"], ["Third Party Materials", "includes", "Third Party Materials"], ["G. Neither Apple", "associated_with", "Apple"]]}, {"text": "reliability, or timeliness of stock information, location data, health information or any other data displayed \nby any Apple Software and Services[ENT0:ORG]. Financial information displayed by any Apple Software[ENT1:ORG] and \nServices is for general informational purposes only and should not be relied upon as investment advice. \nBefore executing any securities transaction based upon information obtained through the Apple \nSoftware and Services[ENT2:ORG], you should consult with a ﬁnancial or securities professional who is legally \nqualiﬁed to give ﬁnancial or securities advice in your country or region. You should evaluate the outputs \ngenerated by artiﬁcial intelligence for accuracy and appropriateness for your use case, including using \nhuman review as appropriate, before using or sharing the outputs from the Apple Software and Services[ENT3:ORG]. \nLocation data provided by any Apple Software and Services[ENT4:ORG], including the Apple Maps[ENT5:ORG] service, is \nprovided for basic navigational and/or planning purposes only and is not intended to be relied upon in \nsituations where precise location information is needed or where erroneous, inaccurate, time-delayed or \nincomplete location data may lead to death, personal injury, or property or environmental damage. You \nagree that the results you receive from the Maps service may vary from actual road or terrain conditions \ndue to factors that can aﬀect the accuracy of the Maps[ENT6:ORG] data, such as, but not limited to, weather, road \nand traﬃc conditions, and geopolitical events. For your safety, always pay attention to posted road signs \nand current road conditions. Follow safe driving practices and traﬃc regulations, and note that cycling \nand walking directions may not include designated pathways.\nH. To the extent that you transmit any content through the use of the Apple Software and Services[ENT7:ORG], you \nrepresent that you own all rights in, or have authorization or are otherwise legally permitted to transmit,", "entities": [["Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Apple \nSoftware and Services", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["Apple Maps", "ORG"], ["Maps", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "ORG"]], "relations": [["Apple Software and Services", "provides", "Apple Software"], ["Apple Software", "provides", "the Apple \nSoftware and Services"], ["the Apple \nSoftware and Services", "provides", "the Apple Software and Services"], ["Apple Software and Services", "includes", "Apple Maps"], ["Apple Maps", "provides", "Maps"], ["Maps", "transmits", "the Apple Software and Services"]]}, {"text": "represent that you own all rights in, or have authorization or are otherwise legally permitted to transmit, \nsuch content and that such content does not violate any terms of service applicable to the Apple \nSoftware and Services[ENT0:ORG]. You agree that the Apple Software and Services[ENT1:ORG] contain proprietary content, \ninformation and material that is owned by Apple[ENT2:ORG], the site owner or their licensors, and is protected by \napplicable intellectual property and other laws, including but not limited to copyright. You agree that you \nwill not use such proprietary content, information or materials other than for permitted use of the Apple \nSoftware and Services[ENT3:ORG] or in any manner that is inconsistent with the terms of this License[ENT4:PERSON] or that \ninfringes any intellectual property rights of a third[ENT5:ORDINAL] party or Apple[ENT6:ORG]. No portion of the Apple Software[ENT7:ORG] and \nServices may be reproduced in any form or by any means. You agree not to modify, rent, lease, loan, \nsell, distribute, or create derivative works based on the Apple Software and Services[ENT8:ORG], in any manner, and \nyou shall not exploit the Apple Software and Services[ENT9:ORG] in any unauthorized way whatsoever, including but \nnot limited to, using the Apple Software and Services[ENT10:ORG] to transmit any computer viruses, worms, trojan \nhorses or other malware, or by trespass or burdening network capacity. You further agree not to use the \nApple Software and Services[ENT11:ORG] in any manner to spam, defraud, harass, abuse, stalk, threaten, defame or \notherwise infringe or violate the rights of any other party, and that Apple[ENT12:ORG] is not in any way responsible for \nany such use by you, nor for any harassing, threatening, defamatory, oﬀensive, infringing or illegal \nmessages or transmissions that you may receive as a result of using any of the Apple Software[ENT13:ORG] and \nServices.\nI. Certain Apple Software, Services[ENT14:ORG], and Third Party Materials[ENT15:ORG] may not be available in all languages or in \nall countries or regions. Apple[ENT16:ORG] makes no representation that such Apple Software, Services[ENT17:ORG], and Third[ENT18:ORDINAL]", "entities": [["the Apple \nSoftware and Services", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple \nSoftware and Services", "ORG"], ["License", "PERSON"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["I. Certain Apple Software, Services", "ORG"], ["Third Party Materials", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Software, Services", "ORG"], ["Third", "ORDINAL"]], "relations": [["the Apple \nSoftware and Services", "contains", "the Apple Software and Services"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "owned_by", "Apple"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "permitted_use", "the Apple \nSoftware and Services"], ["Apple", "is_related_to", "Apple"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "is_related_to", "the Apple Software and Services"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "is_related_to", "the Apple Software and Services"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "is_related_to", "Apple Software and Services"], ["Apple", "is_related_to", "Apple"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "is_related_to", "I. Certain Apple Software, Services"], ["the Apple Software and Services", "is_related_to", "Apple Software, Services"]]}, {"text": "all countries or regions. Apple[ENT0:ORG] makes no representation that such Apple Software, Services[ENT1:ORG], and Third[ENT2:ORDINAL] \nParty Materials[ENT3:ORG] are appropriate or available for use in any particular location. To the extent you choose \nto use or access such Apple Software, Services[ENT4:ORG], or Third Party Materials[ENT5:ORG], you do so at your own initiative \nand are responsible for compliance with any applicable laws, including but not limited to applicable local \nlaws and privacy and data collection laws. Apple[ENT6:ORG] and its licensors reserve the right to change, suspend, \nremove, or disable access to any Apple Software and Services[ENT7:ORG] at any time without notice. In no event \nwill Apple[ENT8:ORG] be liable for the removal of or disabling of access to any such Apple Software and Services[ENT9:ORG]. \nApple[ENT10:ORG] may also impose limits on the use of or access to certain Apple Software and Services[ENT11:ORG], in any \ncase and without notice or liability.7. Termination. This License is eﬀective until terminated. Your rights under this License[ENT12:ORG] will terminate \nautomatically or otherwise cease to be eﬀective without notice from Apple[ENT13:ORG] if you fail to comply with any \nterm(s) of this License[ENT14:ORG]. Upon the termination of this License[ENT15:ORG], you shall cease all use of the Apple \nSoftware[ENT16:ORG] and destroy all copies, full or partial, of the Apple Software[ENT17:ORG]. Sections 5[ENT18:CARDINAL], 6[ENT19:DATE], 7[ENT20:DATE], 8[ENT21:DATE], 9[ENT22:DATE], 11[ENT23:DATE], 12[ENT24:DATE] and \n13[ENT25:CARDINAL] of this License[ENT26:ORG] shall survive any such termination.\n8[ENT27:CARDINAL]. Disclaimer of Warranties.\nA. If you are a customer who is a consumer (someone who uses the Apple Software[ENT28:ORG] outside of your \ntrade, business or profession), you may have legal rights in your country of residence which would \nprohibit the following limitations from applying to you, and where prohibited they will not apply to you. \nTo ﬁnd out more about rights, you should contact a local consumer advice organization. For consumers \nin Australia[ENT29:GPE], nothing in this License[ENT30:ORG] aﬀects, or is intended to aﬀect, your statutory rights under the \nAustralian Consumer Law (including the consumer guarantees).", "entities": [["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Software, Services", "ORG"], ["Third", "ORDINAL"], ["Party Materials", "ORG"], ["Apple Software, Services", "ORG"], ["Third Party Materials", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Apple Software and Services", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"], ["the Apple \nSoftware", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["5", "CARDINAL"], ["6", "DATE"], ["7", "DATE"], ["8", "DATE"], ["9", "DATE"], ["11", "DATE"], ["12", "DATE"], ["13", "CARDINAL"], ["License", "ORG"], ["8", "CARDINAL"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Australia", "GPE"], ["License", "ORG"]], "relations": [["Apple", "uses", "Apple Software, Services"], ["Apple Software, Services", "includes", "Party Materials"], ["Apple Software, Services", "includes", "Apple Software, Services"], ["Apple Software, Services", "includes", "Apple Software and Services"], ["Apple Software, Services", "includes", "Apple Software and Services"], ["Apple Software, Services", "includes", "Apple Software and Services"], ["Apple Software, Services", "includes", "License"], ["Apple Software, Services", "related_to", "License"], ["Apple", "related_to", "Apple"], ["License", "related_to", "License"], ["Apple Software", "related_to", "Australia"]]}, {"text": "in Australia[ENT0:GPE], nothing in this License[ENT1:ORG] aﬀects, or is intended to aﬀect, your statutory rights under the \nAustralian Consumer Law (including the consumer guarantees).\nB. YOU EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGE AND AGREE THAT, TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY \nAPPLICABLE LAW, USE OF THE APPLE SOFTWARE AND ANY SERVICES PERFORMED BY OR \nACCESSED THROUGH THE APPLE SOFTWARE IS AT YOUR SOLE RISK AND THAT THE ENTIRE RISK \nAS TO SATISFACTORY QUALITY, PERFORMANCE, ACCURACY AND EFFORT IS WITH YOU.\nC. TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW, THE APPLE SOFTWARE[ENT2:ORG] AND \nSERVICES ARE PROVIDED “AS IS” AND “AS AVAILABLE”, WITH ALL FAULTS AND WITHOUT \nWARRANTY OF ANY KIND, AND APPLE[ENT3:ORG] AND APPLE[ENT4:ORG]’S LICENSORS (COLLECTIVELY REFERRED TO \nAS “APPLE[ENT5:ORG]” FOR THE PURPOSES OF SECTIONS 8 AND 9) HEREBY DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES \nAND CONDITIONS WITH RESPECT TO THE APPLE SOFTWARE AND SERVICES[ENT6:ORG], EITHER EXPRESS, \nIMPLIED[ENT7:ORG] OR STATUTORY, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES AND/OR \nCONDITIONS OF MERCHANTABILITY, SATISFACTORY QUALITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR \nPURPOSE, ACCURACY, QUIET ENJOYMENT, AND NON-INFRINGEMENT OF THIRD[ENT8:ORDINAL] PARTY RIGHTS.\nD. APPLE DOES NOT WARRANT AGAINST INTERFERENCE WITH YOUR ENJOYMENT OF THE APPLE \nSOFTWARE AND SERVICES, THAT THE FUNCTIONS CONTAINED IN, OR SERVICES PERFORMED OR \nPROVIDED BY, THE APPLE SOFTWARE[ENT9:ORG] WILL MEET YOUR REQUIREMENTS, THAT THE OPERATION[ENT10:EVENT] \nOF THE APPLE SOFTWARE AND SERVICES[ENT11:ORG] WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED OR ERROR-FREE, THAT ANY \nSERVICES WILL CONTINUE TO BE MADE AVAILABLE, THAT DEFECTS IN THE APPLE SOFTWARE OR \nSERVICES WILL BE CORRECTED, OR THAT THE APPLE SOFTWARE OR[ENT12:ORG] SERVICES WILL BE \nCOMPATIBLE OR WORK WITH ANY THIRD[ENT13:ORDINAL] PARTY SOFTWARE, APPLICATIONS[ENT14:ORG] OR THIRD PARTY \nSERVICES. INSTALLATION OF THIS APPLE SOFTWARE MAY AFFECT THE AVAILABILITY AND \nUSABILITY[ENT15:ORDINAL] OF THIRD[ENT16:ORDINAL] PARTY SOFTWARE, APPLICATIONS[ENT17:ORG] OR THIRD[ENT18:ORDINAL] PARTY SERVICES, AS WELL AS \nAPPLE PRODUCTS AND SERVICES.\nE. YOU FURTHER ACKNOWLEDGE THAT THE APPLE SOFTWARE[ENT19:ORG] AND SERVICES ARE NOT", "entities": [["Australia", "GPE"], ["License", "ORG"], ["THE APPLE SOFTWARE", "ORG"], ["APPLE", "ORG"], ["APPLE", "ORG"], ["APPLE", "ORG"], ["THE APPLE SOFTWARE AND SERVICES", "ORG"], ["IMPLIED", "ORG"], ["THIRD", "ORDINAL"], ["THE APPLE SOFTWARE", "ORG"], ["OPERATION", "EVENT"], ["THE APPLE SOFTWARE AND SERVICES", "ORG"], ["THE APPLE SOFTWARE OR", "ORG"], ["THIRD", "ORDINAL"], ["APPLICATIONS", "ORG"], ["USABILITY", "ORDINAL"], ["THIRD", "ORDINAL"], ["APPLICATIONS", "ORG"], ["THIRD", "ORDINAL"], ["THE APPLE SOFTWARE", "ORG"]], "relations": [["Australia", "affects", "License"], ["THE APPLE SOFTWARE", "is_part_of", "APPLE"], ["APPLE", "is_referred_to_as", "APPLE"], ["THE APPLE SOFTWARE", "provides", "THE APPLE SOFTWARE AND SERVICES"], ["THE APPLE SOFTWARE", "is_part_of", "THE APPLE SOFTWARE AND SERVICES"], ["THE APPLE SOFTWARE OR", "is_related_to", "APPLICATIONS"], ["THIRD", "is_related_to", "USABILITY"], ["THIRD", "is_related_to", "APPLICATIONS"]]}, {"text": "USABILITY OF THIRD PARTY SOFTWARE[ENT0:ORG], APPLICATIONS[ENT1:ORG] OR THIRD[ENT2:ORDINAL] PARTY SERVICES, AS WELL AS \nAPPLE PRODUCTS AND SERVICES.\nE. YOU FURTHER ACKNOWLEDGE THAT THE APPLE SOFTWARE[ENT3:ORG] AND SERVICES ARE NOT \nINTENDED OR SUITABLE FOR USE IN SITUATIONS OR ENVIRONMENTS WHERE THE FAILURE OR \nTIME DELAYS OF, OR ERRORS OR INACCURACIES IN THE CONTENT[ENT4:ORG], DATA OR INFORMATION \nPROVIDED BY THE APPLE SOFTWARE OR[ENT5:ORG] SERVICES COULD LEAD TO DEATH, PERSONAL INJURY, \nOR SEVERE PHYSICAL OR ENVIRONMENTAL DAMAGE, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION THE \nOPERATION OF NUCLEAR FACILITIES[ENT6:EVENT], AIRCRAFT NAVIGATION OR COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS, \nAIR TRAFFIC CONTROL, LIFE SUPPORT OR WEAPONS SYSTEMS.\nF. NO ORAL OR WRITTEN INFORMATION OR ADVICE GIVEN BY APPLE[ENT7:ORG] OR AN APPLE[ENT8:ORG] AUTHORIZED \nREPRESENTATIVE SHALL CREATE A WARRANTY. SHOULD THE APPLE SOFTWARE OR SERVICES \nPROVE DEFECTIVE, YOU ASSUME THE ENTIRE COST OF ALL NECESSARY SERVICING, REPAIR OR \nCORRECTION.  SOME JURISDICTIONS DO NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OF IMPLIED WARRANTIES \nOR LIMITATIONS ON APPLICABLE STATUTORY RIGHTS OF A CONSUMER, SO THE ABOVE EXCLUSION AND LIMITATIONS MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU.\n9[ENT9:CARDINAL]. Limitation of Liability. EXCEPT AS OTHERWISE PROVIDED IN THIS LICENSE, TO THE EXTENT \nNOT PROHIBITED BY APPLICABLE LAW, IN NO EVENT SHALL APPLE, ITS AFFILIATES, AGENTS OR \nPRINCIPALS BE LIABLE FOR PERSONAL INJURY, OR ANY INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, INDIRECT OR \nCONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES WHATSOEVER, INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, DAMAGES FOR \nLOSS OF PROFITS, CORRUPTION OR LOSS OF DATA, FAILURE TO TRANSMIT OR RECEIVE ANY \nDATA OR INFORMATION (INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION COURSE INSTRUCTIONS, \nASSIGNMENTS AND MATERIALS), BUSINESS INTERRUPTION OR ANY OTHER COMMERCIAL \nDAMAGES OR LOSSES, ARISING OUT OF OR RELATED TO YOUR USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE \nAPPLE SOFTWARE OR[ENT10:ORG] SERVICES OR ANY THIRD[ENT11:ORDINAL] PARTY SOFTWARE, APPLICATIONS[ENT12:ORG] OR SERVICES \nIN CONJUNCTION WITH THE APPLE SOFTWARE OR SERVICES, HOWEVER CAUSED, REGARDLESS \nOF THE THEORY OF LIABILITY (CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE) AND EVEN IF APPLE[ENT13:ORG] HAS BEEN", "entities": [["USABILITY OF THIRD PARTY SOFTWARE", "ORG"], ["APPLICATIONS", "ORG"], ["THIRD", "ORDINAL"], ["THE APPLE SOFTWARE", "ORG"], ["CONTENT", "ORG"], ["THE APPLE SOFTWARE OR", "ORG"], ["OPERATION OF NUCLEAR FACILITIES", "EVENT"], ["APPLE", "ORG"], ["APPLE", "ORG"], ["9", "CARDINAL"], ["APPLE SOFTWARE OR", "ORG"], ["THIRD", "ORDINAL"], ["APPLICATIONS", "ORG"], ["APPLE", "ORG"]], "relations": [["USABILITY OF THIRD PARTY SOFTWARE", "related_to", "APPLICATIONS"], ["THE APPLE SOFTWARE", "related_to", "THE APPLE SOFTWARE OR"], ["THE APPLE SOFTWARE", "provides", "CONTENT"], ["APPLE", "related_to", "APPLE"], ["APPLE", "related_to", "APPLE SOFTWARE OR"], ["THIRD", "related_to", "APPLICATIONS"], ["THE APPLE SOFTWARE", "related_to", "APPLE SOFTWARE OR"]]}, {"text": "IN CONJUNCTION WITH THE APPLE SOFTWARE OR SERVICES, HOWEVER CAUSED, REGARDLESS \nOF THE THEORY OF LIABILITY (CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE) AND EVEN IF APPLE[ENT0:ORG] HAS BEEN \nADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES. SOME JURISDICTIONS DO NOT ALLOW THE \nEXCLUSION OR LIMITATION OF LIABILITY FOR PERSONAL INJURY, OR OF INCIDENTAL OR \nCONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, SO THIS LIMITATION MAY[ENT1:DATE] NOT APPLY TO YOU. In no event shall \nApple[ENT2:ORG]’s total liability to you for all damages (other than as may be required by applicable law in cases \ninvolving personal injury) exceed the amount of two hundred[ENT3:CARDINAL] and ﬁfty dollars (U.S.$250.00).  The \nforegoing limitations will apply even if the above stated remedy fails of its essential purpose. \nNOTWITHSTANDING ANY OTHER TERMS IN THIS LICENSE, IF THE CONSUMER CONTRACT ACT OF \nJAPAN[ENT4:GPE] APPLIES, TERMS WHICH LIMIT APPLE[ENT5:ORG]’S LIABILITY FOR DAMAGES ARISING FROM BREACH \nOF THE CONTRACT OR TORT COMMITTED BY APPLE SHALL NOT APPLY IF SUCH DAMAGE IS DUE \nTO APPLE[ENT6:ORG]’S INTENTIONAL MISCONDUCT OR GROSS NEGLIGENCE.\n10[ENT7:CARDINAL]. Export Control. You may not use or otherwise export or reexport the Apple Software[ENT8:ORG] except as \nauthorized by United States[ENT9:GPE] law and the laws of the jurisdiction(s) in which the Apple Software[ENT10:ORG] was \nobtained. In particular, but without limitation, the Apple Software[ENT11:ORG] may not be exported or re-exported (a) \ninto any U.S.[ENT12:GPE] embargoed countries or (b) to anyone on the U.S. Treasury Department[ENT13:ORG]’s list of Specially \nDesignated Nationals or the U.S. Department of Commerce Denied Person’s[ENT14:ORG] List or Entity List or any \nother restricted party lists. By using the Apple Software[ENT15:ORG], you represent and warrant that you are not \nlocated in any such country or on any such list. You also agree that you will not use the Apple Software[ENT16:ORG] \nfor any purposes prohibited by United States[ENT17:GPE] law, including, without limitation, the development, design, \nmanufacture or production of missiles, nuclear, chemical or biological weapons.", "entities": [["APPLE", "ORG"], ["MAY", "DATE"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["two hundred", "CARDINAL"], ["JAPAN", "GPE"], ["APPLE", "ORG"], ["APPLE", "ORG"], ["10", "CARDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["United States", "GPE"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["U.S.", "GPE"], ["the U.S. Treasury Department", "ORG"], ["the U.S. Department of Commerce Denied Person’s", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["Apple Software", "ORG"], ["United States", "GPE"]], "relations": [["APPLE", "is_related_to", "Apple"], ["APPLE", "is_related_to", "APPLE"], ["the Apple Software", "is_related_to", "the Apple Software"], ["the Apple Software", "is_related_to", "the Apple Software"], ["United States", "is_related_to", "United States"]]}, {"text": "for any purposes prohibited by United States[ENT0:GPE] law, including, without limitation, the development, design, \nmanufacture or production of missiles, nuclear, chemical or biological weapons.\n11[ENT1:CARDINAL]. Government End Users. The Apple Software[ENT2:ORG] and related documentation are “Commercial \nProducts”, as that term is deﬁned at 48[ENT3:CARDINAL] C.F.R.[ENT4:ORG] §2.101[ENT5:CARDINAL], consisting of “Commercial Computer Software[ENT6:ORG]” \nand “Commercial Computer Software Documentation[ENT7:ORG]”, as such terms are used in 48[ENT8:CARDINAL] C.F.R.[ENT9:ORG] §12.212[ENT10:CARDINAL] or \n48[ENT11:CARDINAL] C.F.R.[ENT12:ORG] §227.7202[ENT13:CARDINAL], as applicable. Consistent with 48[ENT14:CARDINAL] C.F.R.[ENT15:ORG] §12.212[ENT16:CARDINAL] or 48[ENT17:CARDINAL] C.F.R.[ENT18:ORG] §227.7202[ENT19:CARDINAL]-1 \nthrough 227.7202-4[ENT20:DATE], as applicable, the Commercial Computer Software[ENT21:ORG] and Commercial Computer \nSoftware Documentation[ENT22:ORG] are being licensed to U.S. Government[ENT23:ORG] end users (a) only as Commercial \nProducts and (b) with only those rights as are granted to all other end users pursuant to the terms and \nconditions herein.  Unpublished-rights reserved under the copyright laws of the United States[ENT24:GPE].\n12[ENT25:CARDINAL]. Controlling Law[ENT26:PERSON] and Severability[ENT27:ORG]. This License[ENT28:ORG] will be governed by and construed in accordance \nwith the laws of the State of California[ENT29:ORG], excluding its conﬂict of law principles. This License shall not be \ngoverned by the United Nations Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods[ENT30:ORG], the \napplication of which is expressly excluded. If you are a consumer based in the United Kingdom[ENT31:GPE], this \nLicense will be governed by the laws of the jurisdiction of your residence. If for any reason a court of \ncompetent jurisdiction ﬁnds any provision, or portion thereof, to be unenforceable, the remainder of this \nLicense shall continue in full force and eﬀect.\n13[ENT32:CARDINAL]. Complete Agreement; Governing Language[ENT33:WORK_OF_ART]. This License constitutes the entire agreement between you and Apple[ENT34:ORG] relating to the Apple Software[ENT35:ORG] and supersedes all prior or contemporaneous \nunderstandings regarding such subject matter.  No amendment to or modiﬁcation of this License[ENT36:ORG] will be", "entities": [["United States", "GPE"], ["11", "CARDINAL"], ["The Apple Software", "ORG"], ["48", "CARDINAL"], ["C.F.R.", "ORG"], ["2.101", "CARDINAL"], ["Commercial Computer Software", "ORG"], ["Commercial Computer Software Documentation", "ORG"], ["48", "CARDINAL"], ["C.F.R.", "ORG"], ["12.212", "CARDINAL"], ["48", "CARDINAL"], ["C.F.R.", "ORG"], ["227.7202", "CARDINAL"], ["48", "CARDINAL"], ["C.F.R.", "ORG"], ["12.212", "CARDINAL"], ["48", "CARDINAL"], ["C.F.R.", "ORG"], ["227.7202", "CARDINAL"], ["227.7202-4", "DATE"], ["the Commercial Computer Software", "ORG"], ["Commercial Computer \nSoftware Documentation", "ORG"], ["U.S. Government", "ORG"], ["the United States", "GPE"], ["12", "CARDINAL"], ["Law", "PERSON"], ["Severability", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"], ["the State of California", "ORG"], ["the United Nations Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods", "ORG"], ["the United Kingdom", "GPE"], ["13", "CARDINAL"], ["Governing Language", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"]], "relations": [["United States", "governed_by", "the United States"], ["The Apple Software", "related_to", "Apple"], ["Apple", "relates_to", "the Apple Software"], ["the State of California", "governed_by", "Law"], ["the United Kingdom", "governed_by", "the State of California"], ["License", "issued_by", "Apple"]]}, {"text": "understandings regarding such subject matter.  No amendment to or modiﬁcation of this License[ENT0:ORG] will be \nbinding unless in writing and signed by Apple[ENT1:ORG]. Any translation of this License[ENT2:ORG] is done for local \nrequirements and in the event of a dispute between the English[ENT3:LANGUAGE] and any non-English versions, the \nEnglish[ENT4:LANGUAGE] version of this License[ENT5:ORG] shall govern, to the extent not prohibited by local law in your jurisdiction.\n14[ENT6:CARDINAL]. Third Party Acknowledgements.\nA. Portions of the Apple Software[ENT7:ORG] may utilize or include third[ENT8:ORDINAL] party software and other copyrighted \nmaterial. Acknowledgements, licensing terms and disclaimers for such material are contained in the \nelectronic documentation for the Apple Software[ENT9:ORG], and your use of such material is governed by their \nrespective terms. Use of the Google Safe Browsing Service[ENT10:ORG] is subject to the Google Terms of Service[ENT11:ORG] \n(https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/terms/) and to Google[ENT12:ORG]’s Privacy Policy (https://\nwww.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).\nB. Certain software libraries and other third[ENT13:ORDINAL] party software included with the Apple Software[ENT14:ORG] are free \nsoftware and licensed under the terms of the GNU General Public License (GPL) or the GNU[ENT15:ORG] Library/\nLesser General Public License[ENT16:ORG] (LGPL), as the case may be. You may obtain a complete machine-\nreadable copy of the source code for such free software under the terms of the GPL or LGPL[ENT17:ORG], as the \ncase may be, without charge except for the cost of media, shipping, and handling, upon written request \nto Apple[ENT18:ORG] at opensource@apple.com. The GPL/LGPL software is distributed in the hope that it will be \nuseful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY[ENT19:ORG], without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or \nFITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  A copy of the GPL[ENT20:ORG] and LGPL[ENT21:ORG] is included with the Apple \nSoftware[ENT22:ORG].\nC. Use of MPEG-4[ENT23:ORG]. This product is licensed under the MPEG-4 Systems Patent Portfolio License[ENT24:ORG] for \nencoding in compliance with the MPEG-4 Systems Standard[ENT25:ORG], except that an additional license and", "entities": [["License", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"], ["English", "LANGUAGE"], ["English", "LANGUAGE"], ["License", "ORG"], ["14", "CARDINAL"], ["A. Portions of the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Google Safe Browsing Service", "ORG"], ["the Google Terms of Service", "ORG"], ["Google", "ORG"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["GNU", "ORG"], ["Lesser General Public License", "ORG"], ["LGPL", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["WARRANTY", "ORG"], ["GPL", "ORG"], ["LGPL", "ORG"], ["the Apple \nSoftware", "ORG"], ["C. Use of MPEG-4", "ORG"], ["the MPEG-4 Systems Patent Portfolio License", "ORG"], ["the MPEG-4 Systems Standard", "ORG"]], "relations": [["License", "signed_by", "Apple"], ["License", "translation_of", "License"], ["English", "language_version", "English"], ["A. Portions of the Apple Software", "utilizes", "the Apple Software"], ["the Google Safe Browsing Service", "subject_to", "the Google Terms of Service"], ["the Apple Software", "request_to", "Apple"], ["WARRANTY", "includes", "GPL"], ["GPL", "includes", "LGPL"], ["the Apple \nSoftware", "licensed_under", "the MPEG-4 Systems Patent Portfolio License"]]}, {"text": "C. Use of MPEG-4. This product is licensed under the MPEG-4 Systems Patent Portfolio License[ENT0:ORG] for \nencoding in compliance with the MPEG-4 Systems Standard[ENT1:ORG], except that an additional license and \npayment of royalties are necessary for encoding in connection with (i) data stored or replicated in \nphysical media which is paid for on a title by title basis and/or (ii) data which is paid for on a title by title \nbasis and is transmitted to an end user for permanent storage and/or use. Such additional license may \nbe obtained from MPEG LA[ENT2:ORG], LLC[ENT3:GPE]. See https://www.mpegla.com for additional details.\nThis product is licensed under the MPEG-4 Visual Patent Portfolio License[ENT4:ORG] for the personal and non-\ncommercial use of a consumer for (i) encoding video in compliance with the MPEG-4 Visual Standard[ENT5:ORG] \n(“MPEG-4 Video”) and/or (ii) decoding MPEG-4 video that was encoded by a consumer engaged in a \npersonal and non-commercial activity and/or was obtained from a video provider licensed by MPEG LA[ENT6:ORG] \nto provide MPEG-4 video. No license is granted or shall be implied for any other use. Additional \ninformation including that relating to promotional, internal and commercial uses and licensing may be \nobtained from MPEG LA[ENT7:ORG], LLC[ENT8:GPE]. See https://www.mpegla.com.\nD. H.264/AVC Notice[ENT9:ORG].  To the extent that the Apple Software[ENT10:ORG] contains AVC[ENT11:ORG] encoding and/or decoding \nfunctionality, commercial use of H.264/AVC requires additional licensing and the following provision \napplies: THE AVC FUNCTIONALITY IN THIS PRODUCT IS LICENSED HEREIN ONLY FOR THE \nPERSONAL AND NON-COMMERCIAL USE OF A CONSUMER TO (i) ENCODE VIDEO IN COMPLIANCE \nWITH THE AVC STANDARD[ENT12:ORG] (“AVC VIDEO”) AND/OR (ii) DECODE AVC VIDEO THAT WAS ENCODED BY \nA CONSUMER ENGAGED IN A PERSONAL AND NON-COMMERCIAL ACTIVITY AND/OR AVC VIDEO \nTHAT WAS OBTAINED FROM A VIDEO PROVIDER LICENSED TO PROVIDE AVC VIDEO. \nINFORMATION REGARDING OTHER USES AND LICENSES MAY BE OBTAINED FROM MPEG LA \nL.L.C.[ENT13:ORG] SEE HTTPS://WWW.MPEGLA.COM[ENT14:GPE].", "entities": [["the MPEG-4 Systems Patent Portfolio License", "ORG"], ["the MPEG-4 Systems Standard", "ORG"], ["MPEG LA", "ORG"], ["LLC", "GPE"], ["the MPEG-4 Visual Patent Portfolio License", "ORG"], ["the MPEG-4 Visual Standard", "ORG"], ["MPEG LA", "ORG"], ["MPEG LA", "ORG"], ["LLC", "GPE"], ["AVC Notice", "ORG"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["AVC", "ORG"], ["THE AVC STANDARD", "ORG"], ["MPEG LA \nL.L.C.", "ORG"], ["HTTPS://WWW.MPEGLA.COM", "GPE"]], "relations": [["the MPEG-4 Systems Patent Portfolio License", "licensed under", "the MPEG-4 Systems Standard"], ["MPEG LA", "associated with", "LLC"], ["the MPEG-4 Visual Patent Portfolio License", "licensed under", "the MPEG-4 Visual Standard"], ["MPEG LA", "associated with", "MPEG LA"], ["AVC Notice", "contains", "the Apple Software"], ["AVC", "compliance with", "THE AVC STANDARD"], ["MPEG LA \nL.L.C.", "associated with", "HTTPS://WWW.MPEGLA.COM"]]}, {"text": "THAT WAS OBTAINED FROM A VIDEO PROVIDER LICENSED TO PROVIDE AVC VIDEO. \nINFORMATION REGARDING OTHER USES AND LICENSES MAY BE OBTAINED FROM MPEG LA \nL.L.C.[ENT0:ORG] SEE HTTPS://WWW.MPEGLA.COM[ENT1:GPE].\nE. AMR Notice[ENT2:ORG]. The Adaptive Multi-Rate (“AMR[ENT3:ORG]”) encoding and decoding functionality in this product is \nnot licensed to perform cellular voice calls, or for use in any telephony products built on the QuickTime \narchitecture for the Windows[ENT4:PRODUCT] platform. The AMR[ENT5:ORG] encoding and decoding functionality in this product is also not licensed for use in a cellular communications infrastructure including:  base stations, base \nstation controllers/radio network controllers, switching centers, and gateways to and from the public \nswitched network.\nF. FAA Notice[ENT6:ORG]. Aircraft Situation Display and National Airspace System Status Information[ENT7:ORG] data \n(collectively “Flight Data[ENT8:PRODUCT]”) displayed through the Apple Software[ENT9:ORG] is generated by the Federal Aviation \nAdministration[ENT10:ORG]. You agree not to redistribute Flight Data[ENT11:ORG] without the prior written consent of the FAA[ENT12:ORG]. \nThe FAA[ENT13:ORG] and Apple[ENT14:ORG] disclaim all warranties, expressed or implied (including the implied warranties of \nmerchantability and ﬁtness for a particular purpose), regarding the use and accuracy of the Flight Data[ENT15:ORG]. \nYou agree that the FAA[ENT16:ORG] and Apple[ENT17:ORG] shall not be liable, either collectively or individually, for any loss, \ndamage, claim, liability, expense, or penalty, or for any indirect, special, secondary, incidental, or \nconsequential damages deriving from the use of the Flight Data[ENT18:ORG]. The Apple Software[ENT19:ORG] is not sponsored or \nendorsed by the FAA[ENT20:ORG]. The FAA[ENT21:ORG] is not responsible for technical or system problems, and you should not \ncontact the FAA[ENT22:ORG] regarding such problems or regarding operational traﬃc ﬂow issues.\nG. Use[ENT23:PERSON] of Adobe Color Proﬁles[ENT24:ORG]. You may use the Adobe Color Proﬁle software included with the Apple[ENT25:ORG] \nSoftware pursuant to this License[ENT26:ORG], but Adobe[ENT27:PERSON] is under no obligation to provide any support for the Color", "entities": [["MPEG LA \nL.L.C.", "ORG"], ["HTTPS://WWW.MPEGLA.COM", "GPE"], ["E. AMR Notice", "ORG"], ["AMR", "ORG"], ["Windows", "PRODUCT"], ["AMR", "ORG"], ["F. FAA Notice", "ORG"], ["National Airspace System Status Information", "ORG"], ["Flight Data", "PRODUCT"], ["the Apple Software", "ORG"], ["the Federal Aviation \nAdministration", "ORG"], ["Flight Data", "ORG"], ["FAA", "ORG"], ["FAA", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Flight Data", "ORG"], ["FAA", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the Flight Data", "ORG"], ["The Apple Software", "ORG"], ["FAA", "ORG"], ["FAA", "ORG"], ["FAA", "ORG"], ["G. Use", "PERSON"], ["Adobe Color Proﬁles", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["License", "ORG"], ["Adobe", "PERSON"]], "relations": [["MPEG LA \nL.L.C.", "provides_information", "HTTPS://WWW.MPEGLA.COM"], ["E. AMR Notice", "is_related_to", "AMR"], ["AMR", "is_used_in", "Windows"], ["F. FAA Notice", "provides_data", "National Airspace System Status Information"], ["the Federal Aviation \nAdministration", "generates", "Flight Data"], ["FAA", "disclaims_warranties", "Apple"], ["FAA", "is_not_responsible_for", "Apple"], ["G. Use", "is_used_with", "Apple"], ["Adobe Color Proﬁles", "is_part_of", "License"]]}, {"text": "Software pursuant to this License[ENT0:ORG], but Adobe[ENT1:PERSON] is under no obligation to provide any support for the Color \nProﬁles[ENT2:ORG] hereunder, including upgrades or future versions of the Proﬁles[ENT3:NORP] or other items. In addition to the \nprovisions of Sections 8[ENT4:CARDINAL] and 9 above, IN NO EVENT WILL ADOBE BE LIABLE TO YOU FOR ANY \nDAMAGES, CLAIMS OR COSTS WHATSOEVER.  The Adobe Color Proﬁle[ENT5